Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to make it to a play.
A character can attack and kill our enemy.
So if we head over to the Warrior Animations folder, I don't think we made an attacking animation for
that character.
So we go into this folder.
And just like the first nine frames, because if we add all the frames, the animation looks a bit kind
of weird.
So just use the first nine, right click on them and go to fractions and create Sprite.
Then if we select all the sprites.
And right click and go create a flipbook.
And we're going to call this player attack.
And if I head inside here, this is a good player talking animation.
We can close this and go to that character and go to that warrior animation source and just add a new
animation sequence and just call this attack.
Then in animation data set the play attack animation we just made.
And the idea here is because we're using this paper Z plugin at this specific frame in the animation,
we're going to shoot a line trace from our player character, and if there's anything in front of us,
we're going to damage it.
So in order to do that at frame, I think here around here, frame five, just right click.
I go add, notify, then new notify.
I just call this attack.
So at this point in our animation, we're going to shoot a line, chase a black actor.
And if that's anything in front of us, we'll take it.
So I'm just going to close this and then head over to my player character.
Go to the player blueprint.
And some free space, just right click and add custom event queries Attack.
And when we call this event, we just drive up here on the fourth line trace or objects where we're
going to start.
We just want to right click and get actor location.
Weather is going to end.
We're going to end at 100 units in front of our character so we can right click and get back to forward
Vector.
Struggle and multiply.
We can right click on this value and split it and then X per value of 100.
I'm going to strike a fair and at.
And just connect these into here.
So we'll end it 100 units in front of our actors location.
The object type we're going to be looking for is going to be the pawn because our warrior will have
a pawn collision.
So I'm just going to drag off object type and for make array.
And here I'm going to select pawn.
Under practice to ignore.
I'm going to drive a fair amount for make and right click and I forget player character so I can't accidentally
hit myself on something.
Then we want to just drag off our hit result.
This will get the data of anything we hit.
We just want to click, break, get result and we want to get the actor we hit and just struggle for
apply damage.
So this applied damage is a node which is built into Unreal Engine.
And basically if we hit on this line trace, we're going to apply damage to it.
So just hook up from here to here and under base damage for now, just put one.
And just so that we can see this under a draw diva type, just make this for duration so that we can
visually see our line when it's in our game.
Next, we head back to our Warrior Animation blueprint.
You'll see here under functions that should be this received net fire attack, which we made when we
created this attack and our attack animation.
Just double click on it.
Then drop in or beep and drag up and to be attacked.
Plus some event we just made.
And go compile.
So when we play this animation inside of our animation blueprint, it's going to cool the attack event
inside of our player character.
So the final thing we need to do is make it so that when we press a certain button, it will call the
attack event.
So if I go edit and go product settings.
And go to input.
I'm going to add a new action mapping and I'm just going to call this attack.
And I'm going to make it so I have to press the left mouse button in order to do the attack event.
I can just close this.
Head back to my lab and I'm just going to right click and pull attack.
Although this time I want the input action attack.
So make sure we select this one.
And when I press the attack one, we just want to go up here and look for do once.
So the reason why I didn't do once is I don't want the player to be able to continuously attack.
There's going to be a bit of a cooldown each time they've attacked.
After this two, once we are going to actually head back to our Warrior Animation brethren.
I'm going to go over to our new state machine and we're going to add a jump node for when our character
is attacking.
So in some free space, if we just right click for Jump.
And I'm just going to call this attack event.
After the attack.
We just want to go to Animation State and call this attack.
If we hadn't sat there just right click and play Attack.
And hook this up here.
Then if we connect from high tech to here.
So in order to leave our tackling, say we're going to wait for our animation to finish playing.
In order to achieve that effect.
We can just right click and call time remaining and we want to start this one time remaining attack.
So when the time remaining of our animation is less than 0.1, so our animation has no point.
1 seconds left.
We're going to transition back to our normal idle slash walking step.
So we'll just focus up here and go compile.
Then if we head back to our player VP.
I can drug in my animation component and look for an instance.
And then I can cool my jump to it.
And I called mine Attack event.
And we can just hook us up here.
And then just going to have a delay.
Foreground around no point 4 seconds.
And then I will hook this into reset.
That way I can only attack every 0.4 seconds.
So I'm just going to double click to make this a bit tidier.
And I can compile and just test this all out.
So if I go play, you can see my character.
If I click the left mouse button, when I reach that frame, you can see that line trace warp here.
So let's just test that.
This works.
My enemy.
I'm going to put my character and enemy in the same layer.
So it's on 20 in the Y axis.
And my enemy is 150, so I want to put it on 20.
And let's just test this out.
So if I go here.
When I hit my enemy, the line trees went green.
There's one more thing we actually need to fix.
If I was to just walk into my enemy or kind of jump on it, I kind of get pushed in the y axis.
So I kind of become out of place with my enemy.
I need to make it so I'll play a character and our enemy can never move from the y axis.
So we can't kind of like be pushed forwards or backwards in order to achieve that effect.
We can go back to our player character, go to character movement, and in details look for constrain.
I just slept constraint a plane and here onto a plane contrary normal just put a value of one in the
y axis and this will ensure that we can't move in the y axis.
We need to do the same for our Scranton character.
So we go over to where it's located, set character, and in details or constraint.
We want to control the plane and put one in the Y axis.
I'm gonna go back to my pipe and just common all the notes.
So I'll just call this figure attack.
And I'll just call this attack event.
Now I'm going to go compile and close this.